BU Records: Summer School, Inclusive: 1926-1949, Bulk: 1927
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Summer School
Inclusive: 1926-1949, Bulk: 1927
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/166
Baylor University
1 document box
BU Records: Summer School collection contains a variety of materials relating to Baylor University’s Summer School program during the years of 1926-1949.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
The Baylor University Summer School was a program offered by Baylor University beginning in 1889-1890. The program was established in order to serve those seeking to earn college credit outside of the normal academic year. This includes Baylor students themselves, high school students looking to earn credits for college, and teachers who were completing their teaching certifications. The school offered a variety of courses including those in education, speech, theater, music, business, and law. Baylor continues to offer summer courses to this day.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Summer School collection consists of materials from 1926-1949, with some undated items. These materials reflect the activities of the Summer School and its dean, T.D. Brooks.
There are two series in this collection. Series I. Administrative Files contains materials such as advertisements for the Summer School and potential lecturers, bulletins for the school, and class schedules and enrollment lists. Series II. Correspondence contains letters requesting information for program and letters between the dean and students.
Arrangement
Prior to processing, this collection was housed in one document box. Most of the correspondence was contained within undated folders organized alphabetically, while the remaining materials were in unorganized stacks. For the current round of processing, materials of the same topic were grouped together.
Currently, this collection contains two series, I. Administrative Files and II. Correspondence. Series I. Administrative Files are organized according to topic while Series II. Correspondence are organized alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/166. Acquired 1979-10-12
Related Resources
Related references
BU Records: Summer School Records, Accession #BU/166, Box 1, Folder 2, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University. Summer School.
Subjects
Baylor University -- Curricula.; Bulletins.; Records (Documents); Summer schools--Texas.
Genres
Advertisements.; Correspondence.
- Administrative Records, 1926-1949, undated.; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains the advertisements, bulletins, and school records for the Baylor University Summer School. The condition of the series is good.
  - Advertisements, 1926-1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1934-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Summer School Enrollments and Schedules, 1926-1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1926-1927, undated.; 2
  This series contains correspondence from T.D. Brooks, the dean of the Summer School, to those outside of the university. The condition of the series is good.
  - Requests for Information, 1926-1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: A-B, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: C-G, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: H-J, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: K-N, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: P-S, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: T-Z, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)